Finding aid to Board of Trustees Records CA.MS.00146
Smith College Archives
Board of Trustees records
1850-2013
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Board of Trustees.
CA.MS.00146
1.25 linear feet (4 containers)
The Board of Trustees records contain materials describing the function, duties, and organization of the Smith College Board of Trustees, including the by-laws, as well as information on various Board members throughout college history.
Historical Note
The Board of Trustees governs many aspects of the college, including financial decisions. Members include the President of the College, the President of the Alumnae Association, the head of student government, alumnae trustees elected by the Alumnae Association, and other regular members elected by the Board of Trustees.
The Board has existed since 1872. In 1889, alumnae trustees were added.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Board of Trustees records contain materials describing the function, duties, and organization of the Smith College Board of Trustees, including the by-laws, as well as information on various members throughout college history. The collection contains records of such activities as building construction, college planning, committees, promotion and tenure, and the election of a new president. The collection includes an alphabetical listing of trustees, as well as more detailed information on several individuals. Types of materials include extensive correspondences, such as letters and memos, newsletters, pamphlets, lists of trustees, by-laws, and newspaper articles.
The Board of Trustees records are organized into four series:
Series I: Meetings and Minutes
Series II: Correspondence
Series II: Committee on Tenure and Promotion
Series IV: Individual Trustee Biographical Files
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
30. Harriet Bliss Ford Papers
30. Dorothy Nepper Marshall Papers
30. Charlotte Cheever Tucker Papers
32. Office of the President Records
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access:
Access to ALL accessions, except for 2018-A-0059, is restricted. See College Archives staff for assistance.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Board of Trustees records were donated to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources in the years 1988, 1990, 1992, 1993, 1995, 2008, 2010, 2013, 2014, and 2017.
- Meetings-Notices of, 1871-1874; 1926 (Box 268, Folder 1)
- Minutes-Discredited, 1888-; 1918; 1916 (Box 268, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1920-1928 (Box 268, Folder 3)
- John M. Greene Award-Euphemia Hare Steffey, '44, 1992 (Box 268, Folder 4)
- John M. Greene Award Citations, 1980-1998 (Box 268, Folder 5)
- John M. Greene Committee, 1985-1990 (Box 268, Folder 6)
- General (Box 269, Folder 1)
- General (Box 269, Folder 2)
- Alumnae Trustees, 1888 (Box 269, Folder 3)
- By-Laws, 1925-1999 (Box 269, Folder 4)
- List Trustees, 1968-1976 (Box 269, Folder 5)
- Correspondence
  - Appointment of a new President, 1917; 1956 (Box 269, Folder 6)
  - Dormitory Construction, 1917 (Box 269, Folder 7)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1916-1917 (Box 269, Folder 8)
  - Infirmary, 1917 (Box 269, Folder 9)
  - Clark L. Seelye to John M. Greene, 1894-1905 (Box 269, Folder 10)
  - Sabbatical Leaves, 1917 (Box 269, Folder 11)
- Meetings and Minutes (Box 269, Folder 12)
- Neilson Chair, 1930-1936 (Box 269, Folder 13)
- Photographs, 1933-1964 (Box 269, Folder 14)
- Planning Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 269, Folder 15)
- Pledges to General Education Board, 1921 (Box 269, Folder 16)
- Allen, Charles H. (Box 269, Folder 17)
- Baldwin, Ruth (Bowles), 1887 (Box 269, Folder 18)
- Baldwin, William H., 1896 (Box 269, Folder 19)
- Ballou, Emily (Crabbe), 1919 (Box 269, Folder 20)
- Brooks, Harvey (Box 269, Folder 21)
- Buck, Paul Herman, 1952-1962 (Box 269, Folder 22)
- Clark, Charles N., 1895-1911 (Box 269, Folder 23)
- Cone, Kate (Morris), 1879 (Box 269, Folder 24)
- Dawes, Anna L.
  - Dawes, Anna L., 1889-1938 (Box 269, Folder 25)
  - Dawes, Anna L.-Correspondence, 1889-1896 (Box 269, Folder 26)
  - Dawes, Anna L.-Correspondence to Charlotte (Cheever) Tucker, 1890-1894 (Box 269, Folder 27)
- Day, Pomeroy, 1951-1960 (Box 269, Folder 28)
- DeConingh, Edward H., 1963 (Box 269, Folder 29)
- Emerson, Kendall, 1917-1935 (Box 269, Folder 30)
- Fosdick, Harry Emerson-Recording (Box 269, Folder 31)
- Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1925-1969 (Box 269, Folder 32)
- Individuals, G-Z (Box 276)
- Committee on Promotion and Tenure
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1920-1923 (Box 270, Folder 1)
    - General, 1923 (Box 270, Folder 2)
    - General, 1924 (Box 270, Folder 3)
    - General, 1925; undated (Box 270, Folder 4)
    - William Allan Neilson and Mary Van Kleeck, 1923-1925 (Box 270, Folder 5)